A Guide to the Papers of Julian Bond, 1897-2006
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I: Articles and Speeches by Julian Bond
  - Speech given at Villanova University, Pennsylvania, concerning race and class, 1975 April 9 (Box-folder 4:23)
  - Remarks prepared for The National Council of Black Child Development, Atlanta, Georgia, 1975 June 26 (Box-folder 4:24)
  - Remarks prepared for the Third Annual Convention/United Youth Adult Conference, Morris Brown College, Atlanta, Georgia, 1975 August 22 (Box-folder 4:25)
  - Remarks prepared for Morehouse College Alumni Association Meeting, Cleveland, Ohio, 1975 August 30 (Box-folder 4:26)
  - Speech for Project Media, Jackson, Mississippi, 1975 September 19 (Box-folder 4:27)
  - Speech before the National Association of FM Broadcasters, Marriott Hotel, [Atlanta, Georgia] on the power of the media, 1975 September 20 (Box-folder 4:28)
  - Speech concerning the Black Ghetto, 1975 October 17 (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Speech concerning black gains as a family affair, Los Angeles, California, 1975 November 18 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Remarks prepared for delivery to the California School Boards Association, Sacramento, California, 1975 December 12 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Speech concerning the power of the media: black journalists, 1975 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Speech concerning the seventies and the black problem, 1975 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Commencement Address, 1975 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Speech concerning the Democratic Party and black people, 1975 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Speech concerning African Liberation, 1975 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - Remarks prepared for the Operation P.U.S.H. Convention, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1975 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - Speech concerning blacks in society and proposed changes, 1975 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - Speech concerning the Jewish question, 1975 (Box-folder 5:11)
  - Speech concerning the 200th Birthday of the United States and black gains, 1975 (Box-folder 5:12)
  - Speech concerning changes in the black struggle, 1975 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - Tribute to Maynard Jackson, Jr., Atlanta's first black mayor (A Roast), 1975 (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Speech concerning drug addiction and the black community, 1975 (Box-folder 5:15)
  - Speech concerning the conditions of black America, 1975 (Box-folder 5:16)
  - Speech concerning equal and integrated education, 1975 (Box-folder 5:17)
  - Minority Cooperation, 1975 (Box-folder 5:18)
  - Speech- School Desegregation in the Seventies: Perspective and Reaffirmation, 1975 (Box-folder 5:19)
  - Speech concerning black politics and influence in the South, 1975 (Box-folder 5:20)
  - Speech concerning young professionals and health care, 1975, 1976 (Box-folder 5:21)
  - Speech concerning blacks in New York City and their condition on the eve of the Bicentennial, [1975] (Box-folder 5:22)
  - Article- Jimmy Carter: A 'Clean' George Wallace? for The Voice, [ca. 1975] (Box-folder 5:23)
  - Speech concerning black America: its progress and its failures, 1976 January (Box-folder 5:24)
  - Press Release- Bond will not be an independent third party candidate for President in 1976, 1976 March 15 (Box-folder 5:25)
  - Speech concerning the status of black people during the Bicentennial Year, 1976 March 20 (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Speech concerning Angola and the tragedy of United States foreign policy in Africa, [New York City?], 1976 Spring (Box-folder 5:27)
  - Political Diary kept by Julian Bond concerning the 1976 Election, 1976 April 11-June 11 (Box-folder 5:28)
  - Speech prepared for Black Democrats Conference, Charlotte, North Carolina- A Last- Minute Strategy for Black Democrats, 1976 April (Box-folder 5:29)
  - Press Release Why I Can't Support Jimmy Carter, 1976 April (Box-folder 5:30)
  - Speech at the Robert F. Kennedy Journalism Award, 1976 [June?] (Box-folder 5:31)
  - Press Release concerning NAACP and Roy Wilkins sent to the Atlanta Inquirer, 1976 July 9 (Box-folder 5:32)
  - Speech concerning the election process and the political democracy, 1976 [September?] (Box-folder 5:33)
  - Speech at the Hungry Club Forum, Atlanta, Georgia, on what the elections mean for Americans, 1976 November 3 (Box-folder 5:34)
  - Speech concerning the elections and their aftermath, 1976 November (Box-folder 5:35)
  - Remarks prepared for The Stadium Club and the West End Rotary Club, Atlanta, Georgia, concerning the future of South Africa, 1976 December 10 (Box-folder 5:36)
  - Remarks prepared for delivery at the Marriott Motor Hotel, Los Angeles, California, concerning the Meharry Medical College, Nashville, Tennessee, 1976 December 11 (Box-folder 5:37)
  - Speech concerning the progress of black people, 1976 (Box-folder 6:1)
  - Speech concerning the struggle of the American underclass, 1976 (Box-folder 6:2)
  - Speech concerning black professionals and their difficult task, 1976 (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Speech concerning crime, justice, and reformers, 1976 (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Speech about looking back upon black history, 1976 (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Speech concerning the struggle of black women in America, 1976 (Box-folder 6:6)
  - Speech concerning blacks in elected office, ca. 1976 (Box-folder 6:7)
  - Speech concerning history of black politics, ca. 1976 (Box-folder 6:8)
  - Remarks concerning Southern economic conditions before The Southern Rural Policy Conference, Atlanta, Georgia, 1977 January 7 (Box-folder 6:9)
  - Article for Black Enterprise about black people being politically impotent, [1977 January 12] (Box-folder 6:10)
  - Tribute to Mrs. Fannie Lou Hamer delivered at her memorial service, Ruleville, Mississippi, 1977 March 20 (Box-folder 6:11)
  - Article about the funeral of Mrs. Fannie Lou Hamer in Ruleville, Mississippi, for Player's Magazine, 1977 [March] (Box-folder 6:12)
  - Statement by Julian Bond concerning the nomination of Atlanta lawyer Griffin Bell for Attorney General by Jimmy Carter, 1977 March (Box-folder 6:13)
  - Article by Julian Bond Civil Rights Movement to the Courtroom in Trial Magazine, 1977 March (Box-folder 6:14)
  - Article by Julian Bond sent to M. Carl Holman of the National Urban Coalition about the new South and its development, 1977 April 21 (Box-folder 6:15)
  - Article by Julian Bond sent to Michael St. John, Player's Magazine concerning the sins of Richard Nixon, 1977 May 24 (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Speech concerning the challenges facing black attorneys presented to the Black American Law Students Association (BALSA), Duquesne Chapter, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1977 May 27 (Box-folder 6:17)
  - Speech- Tips to the Traveling Speaker, a humorous look at potential pitfalls for the professional speech maker, 1977 June 7 (Box-folder 6:18)
  - Article of tribute to Fannie Lou Hamer in Ebony Magazine, 1977 June 13 (Box-folder 6:19)
  - Article on Jimmy Carter's success in Playboy Magazine, 1977 June (Box-folder 6:20)
  - Comments made at a political roast to raise money for the Henry Hutchins City Council Campaign, 1977 July 2 (Box-folder 6:21)
  - Synopsis of the reprise telecast of NBC's Saturday Night Live, 1977 August 4 (Box-folder 6:22)
  - Remarks prepared for the Annual Banquet, Laymen's Department, the Progressive National Baptist Convention, Inc., at the Peachtree Plaza Hotel, Atlanta, Georgia, 1977 August 9 (Box-folder 6:23)
  - Remarks prepared for the National Student's Association, Houston, Texas, concerning the impact of student involvement, with press release, 1977 August 15 (Box-folder 6:24)
  - Article-News Stories We'd Like to See in Players Magazine, 1977 September (Box-folder 6:25)
  - Remarks prepared for delivery at the 35th Georgia NAACP Convention, Macon Hilton, Macon, Georgia, concerning the future of black Georgians, 1977 November 12 (Box-folder 6:26)
  - Speech concerning the debate over the Supreme Court case Bakke v Regents and affirmative action, given at Paschal's Motor Hotel, Atlanta, Georgia, 1977 November 29 (Box-folder 6:27)
  - Speech concerning black people and the future, 1977 (Box-folder 6:28)
  - Speech concerning political diversity, 1977 (Box-folder 6:29)
  - Report on the SNCC meeting in Atlanta, Georgia, in the Los Angeles Times, 1977 (Box-folder 6:30)
  - Speech concerning the phenomenon of black voter support for Jimmy Carter, 1977 (Box-folder 6:31)
  - Speech- Strategies for Change The Texas Regional Conference on Alternative Policies, Arlington, Texas, 1978 February 4 (Box-folder 6:32)
  - Remarks delivered to National Drug Abuse Conference 1978, Seattle, Washington, and with some revision to the Minnesota Social Service Association, Duluth, Minnesota, on April 9, 1978, 1978 April 5, 9 (Box-folder 6:33)
  - Speech- What's Next? before the Psychiatric Association Conference, Atlanta, Georgia, 1978 May 10 (Box-folder 6:34)
  - Article- Issues After Bakke: Who Gets in the Lifeboat? in Collage, 1978 December (Box-folder 6:35)
  - Speech concerning American race relations, Portland Motor Lodge, 1978 (Box-folder 6:36)
  - Speeches about poverty, 1978, 1985 (Box-folder 7:1)
  - Speech concerning education and the Bakke v Regents decision, ca. 1978 (Box-folder 7:2)
  - Article concerning the victory of Proposition 13 in California and its Implications, [ca. 1978] (Box-folder 7:3)
  - Speech about fulfilling the dream of Martin Luther King, Jr. through political action, 1979 January 13 (Box-folder 7:4)
  - Speech commemorating the 50th Anniversary of the Birth of Martin Luther King, Jr., 1979 Jan [15?] (Box-folder 7:5)
  - Article- What Next? in The Pennsylvania Gazette (Box-folder 7:6)
  - Article- Better Voters, Better Politicians in Southern Exposure, 1979 Spring (Box-folder 7:7)
  - Remarks prepared for delivery to The Grant Wood Area Education Agency, Cedar Rapids, Iowa, concerning education as the most important function of state and local governments, 1979 August 19 (Box-folder 7:8)
  - Remarks to the Triad Sickle Cell Anemia Foundation, Greensboro, North Carolina, 1979 September 16 (Box-folder 7:9)
  - Speech to the Lake County Association of Black Communicators, Gary, Indiana, concerning the power of the media, 1979 September 30 (Box-folder 7:10)
  - Speech concerning black education and the 25th Anniversary of Brown v the Board of Education, Topeka, Kansas, 1979 (Box-folder 7:11)
  - Speech concerning economic equality, 1979 (Box-folder 7:12)
  - Remarks prepared for delivery to the Kansas National Education Association, Wichita, Kansas, concerning education in Georgia, 1980 April 11 (Box-folder 7:13)
  - Speech before the Hungry Club Forum, Atlanta, Georgia, about black voter apathy, 1980 May 21 (Box-folder 7:14)
  - Speech concerning housing for minorities and the poor, prepared for Julian Bond by Renee Huie, 1980 October 2 (Box-folder 7:15)
  - Remarks prepared for delivery to the Michigan Association of Media Educators concerning education and black people, 1980 October 9 (Box-folder 7:16)
  - Remarks prepared for delivery to the National Legal Aid and Defender Association, El Centro Convention Center, San Juan, Puerto Rico, concerning the Reagan Administration outlook, 1980 November 13 (Box-folder 7:17)
  - Speech concerning student protests, ca. 1980 (Box-folder 7:18)
  - Speech concerning black families, Hampton Institute, Virginia, 1981 March 26 (Box-folder 7:19)
  - Speech concerning the immigrant's plight, The University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1981 April 2 (Box-folder 7:20)
  - Remarks prepared for delivery to the International Longshoremen and Warehouse Union, Honolulu, Hawaii, concerning the movement for political and economic justice, 1981 April 29 (Box-folder 7:21)
  - Speech concerning the abuses of the Ku Klux Klan, 1981 April 28 (Box-folder 7:22)
  - Remarks prepared for delivery to the Consultation on Police and the Minority Community, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, Colorado, 1981 August 15 (Box-folder 7:23)
  - Speech concerning black disenfranchisement, Los Angeles, California, 1981 September 19 (Box-folder 7:24)
  - Speech concerning the Voting Rights Act in 1982, 1982 (Box-folder 7:25)
  - Speech concerning Ronald Reagan, 1982 (Box-folder 7:26)
  - Remarks prepared for delivery to the National Association of Black Journalists, The Fairmont Hotel, New Orleans, Louisiana, concerning a black presidential candidate, 1983 September 8 (Box-folder 7:27)
  - Remarks prepared for delivery to the Black American Political Association of California, Sacramento, California, concerning a black presidential candidate, 1983 October 8 (Box-folder 7:28)
  - Speech concerning the Reagan Administration and Civil Rights, 1983 (Box-folder 7:29)
  - Speech attacking the Reagan Administration's civil rights enforcement record delivered as the keynote speaker at the dinner celebration of 20th Anniversary of the passage of the 1964 Civil rights Act by the Boston Lawyers Committee for Civil Rights Under Law, 1984 June 23 (Box-folder 7:30)
  - Speech concerning the re-election of Ronald Reagan, 1984 November 14 (Box-folder 7:31)
  - Speech challenging the American character, 1984 (Box-folder 7:32)
  - Speech concerning politics and poverty, ca. 1984 (Box-folder 7:33)
  - Speech concerning the Reagan Justice Department, 1985 April (Box-folder 7:34)
  - Speech concerning the death penalty as morally wrong, 1985 May 10 (Box-folder 7:35)
  - Speech concerning Georgia's education system, 1985 (Box-folder 7:36)
  - Speech concerning Central America and Nicaragua, 1985 (Box-folder 7:37)
  - Speech concerning the relationship between the United States and South Africa, 1985 (Box-folder 7:38)
  - Speech concerning remembering the past, 1985 (Box-folder 8:1)
  - Speech delivered to the Executive Committee of the League of United Latin American Citizens, American Hotel about building communication between black and Latin American citizens, 1986 March 14 (Box-folder 8:2)
  - Speech concerning politics and Democratic ideology, 1986 (Box-folder 8:3)
  - Speech- Bicentennial Speech- Blacks and the Constitution NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund, Inc., 1987 March (Box-folder 8:4)
  - Remarks prepared for delivery to the Alliance for Children, Youth and Families, Seattle, Washington, 1987 June 11 (Box-folder 8:5)
  - Remarks prepared for the Opening Conference-20th Anniversary of the Fair Housing Act of 1968, Des Moines, Iowa, 1988 April 8 (Box-folder 8:6)
  - Keynote Address at the New Directions in Civil Rights Conference, 1988 May 4 (Box-folder 8:7)
  - Speech concerning the Voting Rights Act Amendments, revisions of Julian Bond speech (incomplete), 1988 October 17 (Box-folder 8:8)
  - Speech concerning discrimination against black voters, 1988 November 1 (Box-folder 8:9)
  - Speech concerning the 1988 Presidential election, 1988 [November] (Box-folder 8:10)
  - Speech concerning equal rights in employment, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1988 December 9 (Box-folder 8:11)
  - Speech concerning a review of race relations in the United States, 1988 (Box-folder 8:12)
  - Speech- A Historical Perspective of a People delivered at the Cheyney University of Pennsylvania, 1989 February (Box-folder 8:13)
  - Speech- Civil Rights and Wrongs Planned Parenthood National Atlantic Region Spring Conference, Washington, D.C., 1989 May 20 (Box-folder 8:14)
  - Speech- Blacks and Jews: Historical Relationship, Drexel University, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1989 May 25 (Box-folder 8:15)
  - Speech concerning the dedication of a memorial monument to Civil Rights Martyrs, Montgomery, Alabama, 1989 (Box-folder 8:16)
  - Article- The Fight Continues: The Civil Rights Movement from the '60s through the '80s, 1990 January (Box-folder 8:17)
  - Paper- The Movement and the Media: An Analysis of Media Coverage of the Southern Civil Rights Movement presented at the 1990 Spring Seminar: Press, Politics and Public Policy, John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University, 1990 April 17 (Box-folder 8:18)
  - Paper- In Commemoration of the 25th Anniversary of the Voting Rights Act of 1965: Race and Politics in Twentieth-century United States. A Participant's Commentary,1990 April 21 (Box-folder 8:19)
    Prepared for delivery before the New England Historical Association, Pine Manor College, Boston, Massachusetts
  - Speech- Race, the Press, Politics Joan Shorenstein Barone Center, John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University, 1990 May 3 (Box-folder 8:20)
  - Speech prepared for Planned Parenthood of Metropolitan Washington Annual Luncheon, Washington, D.C., 1990 May 24 (Box-folder 8:21)
  - Paper- The Impact of Student Activism on Black Politics, 1965-1968, 1990 November 2 (Box-folder 8:22)
    Prepared for delivery at the annual meeting of the Southern Historical Association, New Orleans, Louisiana.
  - Speech concerning the struggle of black people to achieve freedom, 1990 (Box-folder 8:23)
  - Speech prepared for the NAACP Northeast Region Voting Rights Seminar, New York, New York, 1991 January 19 (Box-folder 8:24)
  - OAH Keynote Address, Louisville, Kentucky, 1991 April 11 (Box-folder 8:25)
    Highlighting the problem of historical ignorance about the Civil Rights movement and the need for affirmative action.
  - Speech- Black Politics, Now and Then delivered at Amherst College, 1991 April 17 (Box-folder 8:26)
  - Speech concerning black crime and violence, delivered at the University of Virginia, Health Sciences Center, Department of Medicine, 1991 April 24 (Box-folder 8:27)
  - Lecture- Southern Student Activism: From Sit-Ins to Black Power presented at Galveston College, The American South Lecture Series, 1991 October 30 (Box-folder 8:28)
  - Speech- The Rising Tide of Racism delivered at the Chicago Public Library, Society in Focus Series of Talks, 1991 November 15 (Box-folder 8:29)
  - Speech- [19]60s Successes and [19]90s Failures1991 (Box-folder 8:30)
  - Speech concerning NAACP and affirmative action, 1992 April 23 (Box-folder 8:31)
  - Article- Civil Rights in the Popular Culture in Southern Changes, 1992 Spring (Box-folder 8:32)
  - Speech concerning the dimensions of Thomas Jefferson's legacy, delivered at the Jefferson Conference, 1992 October 16 (Box-folder 8:33)
  - Speech concerning racism and the centrality of race in American life, 1992 (Box-folder 8:34)
  - Speech concerning Civil Rights movement and affirmative action, 1992 (Box-folder 8:35)
  - Paper- Some Questions for Examining Pennsylvania's Black History delivered at the [15th Annual Black History in Pennsylvania Conference], [1992] (Box-folder 8:36)
  - Commencement speech given at the University of Virginia Law School, 1993 May 21 (Box-folder 9:1)
  - Speech- Heroes, Hope and History, 1993 November 5 (Box-folder 9:2)
  - Speech concerning on how the new administration has brought our long national nightmare to an end and a review of the recent era of American politics, 1993 (Box-folder 9:3)
  - Introduction for May It Please the Court concerning Cooper v Aaron, [1993?] (Box-folder 9:4)
  - Speech delivered at the New Jersey Black Issues Convention concerning the history of the Civil Rights movement, 1994 October (Box-folder 9:5)
  - Speech- Historical Perspectives on Fair Lending prepared for the Fair Lending Seminar for Chief Executive Officers, Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council, San Francisco, California, 1994 November 4 (Box-folder 9:6)
  - Speech- The 1965 Voting Rights Act, A Beneficiary's Commentary, 1995 April 1 (Box-folder 9:7)
  - ) Lecture- Crossing the Color Line: R & B and the Birth of Rock 'n' Roll given at the National Endowment for the Humanities Summer Institute, Harvard University, 1995 July 17, Teaching the History of the Southern Civil Rights Movement, 1865 to 1965. (Box-folder 9:8)
  - Speech concerning Flags as Powerful Symbols before the Southern Historical Association, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1995 November 10 (Box-folder 9:9)
  - Speech- The Impact of Student Activism on Black Politics, 1995 (Box-folder 9:10)
  - Speech- In Commemoration of the 30th Anniversary of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 A Participant's Commentary, 1995 (Box-folder 9:11)
  - Speech- Acting Affirmatively concerning affirmative action, 1995 (Box-folder 9:12)
  - Speech concerning the Anniversary of the Fair Housing Act, 1995 (Box-folder 9:13)
  - Speech concerning the recent elections and the effect of the Republican majority and the Contract with America, 1995 (Box-folder 9:14)
  - Speech- Louis Farrakhan, The Million Man March and the NAACP, 1995 (Box-folder 9:15)
  - Article- Passing the Torch? The New Generation of Student Activists in The Black Collegian, 1996 April (Box-folder 9:16)
  - Speech concerning civic participation and the Dixiecratization of America delivered in Nashville, Tennessee, 1996 September 27 (Box-folder 9:17)
  - Speech- Heroes, Hope and History concerning the Civil Rights Movement, Missouri Historical Society, 1996 November 8 (Box-folder 9:18)
  - Paper- Atlanta: Protest to Politics: A Brief History 1870 to 1980, 1997 January 12 (Box-folder 9:19)
  - Speech- Labor Teach-in, 1997 February 27 (Box-folder 9:20)
  - Speech concerning the challenges faced by the teachers and scholars of the 20th century struggle for civil rights, University of Virginia, 1997 June 28 (Box-folder 9:21)
  - Speech- At the Turn of Two Centuries Keynote Address at the Washington- Du Bois Symposium, Roanoke, Virginia, 1998 March 20 (Box-folder 9;22)
  - Meet the Press NBC News concerning the legacy of Martin Luther King, Jr., 1998 April 5 (Box-folder 9:23)
  - Speech concerning the Civil Rights Movement and the media, delivered at the Martin Luther King Jr. Conference, University of Newcastle, Newcastle upon Tyne, 1998 May 7-10 (Box-folder 9:24)
  - Speech- Civil Rights, Now & Then at The National Press Club, 1998 May 27 (Box-folder 9:25)
  - Briefing Paper on the Attacks on African American Voters in the Alabama Black Belt prepared for Meeting with U.S. Attorney General Janet Reno, Julian Bond as a Member of the Delegation, 1998 June 11 (Box-folder 9:26)
  - Speech- Civil Rights, Now & Then delivered at the Philadelphia Bar Association, 1998 June 18 (Box-folder 9:27)
  - Speech concerning the relationship between the NAACP and organized labor delivered at the United Auto Workers Convention, Las Vegas, Nevada, 1998 June 25 (Box-folder 9:28)
  - Speech- The NAACP- Yesterday, Today, and Tomorrow delivered at the NAACP Convention Public Mass Meeting, Georgia World Congress Center, Atlanta, Georgia, 1998 July 12 (Box-folder 9:29)
  - Speech- The 1965 Voting Rights Act, A Beneficiary's Perspective, 1998 October 2 (Box-folder 9:30)
  - Speech- Aaron Henry Commemoration, 1999 July 2 (Box-folder 10:1)
    For this former head of the Mississippi NAACP organization and well-know civil rights figure.
  - Address at the 90th Annual NAACP Convention, New York, New York, 1999 July 11 (Box-folder 10:2)
  - Speech concerning the structure and operation of the NAACP and its renewed relationship with Harvard University, delivered at the Harvard Business School, 1999 December 3 (Box-folder 10:3)
  - Speech- Civil Rights, Now & Then delivered at the University of California, Los Angeles, California, 1999 (Box-folder 10:4)
  - Speech concerning the celebration of the anniversary of Brown v Board of Education and discussing the closing of the Prince Edward County schools, delivered at Prince Edward County, Virginia, 1999 (Box-folder 10:5)
  - Speech concerning Affirmative Action, 1999 (Box-folder 10:6)
  - Paper- The Media and the Movement: Looking Back from the Southern Front, [1999?] (Box-folder 10:7)
  - Commencement Address at St. George's University, [Grenada?], 2000 May 12 (Box-folder 10:8)
  - Commencement Address at Washington University, 2000 May 19 (Box-folder 10:9)
  - Speech for the 91st NAACP Convention, Baltimore, Maryland, 2000 July 9 (Box-folder 10:10)
  - Speech- SNCC: What We Did, 2000 (Box-folder 10:11)
  - Speeches-A Race Odyssey used in successive years, 2000, 2001, 2002 (Box-folder 10:12)
  - Speech concerning the historic relationship between Blacks and Jews, 2000 (Box-folder 10:13)